Finding aid for the Nikki R. Keddie papers LSC.1789
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Series 3: Research files., circa 1950-2003
  - Clippings. Various topics., 1965-1997 (Box 17, Folder 3-5)
  - Djamalzadeh, Ivanov, and other summaries., undated (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Fundamentalism research materials., 1984-1990 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Fundamentalism. Turkey research materials., undated (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Iran research materials and notes., circa 1955-1999 (Box 17, Folder 9-17, Box 19, Folder 1-2, Box 18, Folder 1-12)
  - Islam research materials and notes., circa 1980-1985 (Box 19, Folder 3-5)
  - Jafri, Sayyid Saghir Husain interview., 1985 October (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Manchester Guardian newspaper., 1974 October 12 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Medical reviews., 1979-1983 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Middle East materials., 1986-1997 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous articles and notes., circa 1990-1999 (Box 19, Folder 21, Folder 10-12)
  - Misztal and Shupe notes., circa 1992 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Nercherye research materials., undated (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Pakistan interviews, and notes., circa 1986-1995 (Box 19, Folder 15-17)
  - Persian texts., undated (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Problems in the Research on Women in the Middle East notes., 1975-1998 (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Religion and Society in Asia and the Middle East research materials., 1978 (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - Revolutions articles., 1988-1990 (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - Shi'ism notes., circa 1990-1995 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Slavery, race, orientalism notes., circa 1990-1995 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Soviet-Iran reprints., circa 1958-1959 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Theory and generalization notes., 2002 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Tobacco Protest notes., 1981 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Turkey articles., 2002-2003 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - U.S. News magazine., 1987 March 30 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Women in Islam articles and notes., circa 1974-1992 (Box 20, Folder 8-9)
  - Women in Middle East research materials., 1982-1998 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Women in Revolutionary Iran. Conference paper by Lois Beck., 1980 (Box 20, Folder 11)
- Series 4: Photographic materials., 1958-1997
  This series is largely made up of color 35 mm slides taken by Keddie on research and leisure to trips throughout the United States, Europe, Asia, and Africa. Keddie's photography focused on people as subjects, but the series also features images of buildings, monuments, and landscapes. Photographs are included as indicated. Materials are organized alphabetically by trip location. If a trip included more than one location, the predominant location is listed first.
  - Boulder to New York trip., 1958 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - California and New Mexico., 1979-1980 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - China., 1958-1982 (Box 34, Folder 1, Box 22, Box 21, Folder 3-7)
  - Club Med., 1983 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Egypt and Italy., 1964 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - England and France., 1986-1987 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - England and Hungary., 1982 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Europe., circa 1965-1992 (Box 22, Folder 6-7, Box 35, Folder 4-5)
  - France, Egypt, and Los Angeles., undated (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Geneva, Switzerland., 1989 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Germany., 1990 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Holland., 1979 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Hungary., 1982 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Idaho and California., 1983 (Box 22, Folder 13-14)
  - Indonesia and Malyasia., 1977-1984 (Box 24, Folder 1, Box 23, Folder 1-7, Box 36)
  - Italy, England, and Malta., 1975 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Italy and Germany., 1985 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Iran., 1960-1990 (Box 25, Folder 1-7, Box 24, Folder 4-9, Box 27, Folder 1-2, Box 37, Folder 1-6, Box 35, Folder 1, Box 26, Box 34, Folder 2-7)
    BOX 37 contains six 9 1/2x14 inch photographic prints mounted on 16x20 board.
  - London and Paris., 1976-1980 (Box 27, Folder 3-8)
  - Los Angeles., 1978-1987 (Box 28, Folder 1-4, Box 27, Folder 9-10)
  - Mexico., 1975-1987 (Box 28, Folder 6-8, Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Mixed., 1959-1997 (Box 28, Folder 9-11, Box 35, Folder 1-3)
  - Morocco and Tunisia., 1976-1989 (Box 29, Folder 1-3, Box 28, Folder 12-13, Box 38, Folder 5)
  - New England and Washington D.C., 1979-1981 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - North Africa., 1978 (Box 29, Folder 5-6)
  - Pakistan., 1985-1986 (Box 29, Folder 7-8, Box 30, Folder 1-5, Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Paris and mixed cities., 1970-1988 (Box 31, Folder 1-2, Box 30, Folder 6-8)
  - Photographs. 3x5 inch, color., undated (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Pier K25, 1975 (Box 31, Folder 4-5)
  - Russia and Morocco., 1983-1984 (Box 31, Folder 6, Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Santa Monica, Venice, and Yosemite, CA., 1983-1988 (Box 31, Folder 7-9)
  - Senegal, Egypt, and Tunisia., 1983-1985 (Box 38, Folder 1-4, Box 32, Folder 1, Box 31, Folder 10-12)
  - South Asia., 1984 (Box 32, Folder 2-3)
  - Southern California., circa 1976-1979 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Spain., 1988 (Box 32, Folder 5-6)
  - Syria., 1985 September-October (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Tunisia., 1977-1978 (Box 32, Folder 8-9)
  - Turkey., 1972 (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - United States., 1958-1990 (Box 33, Folder 1-5, Box 35, Folder 6-7)
  - Washington DC, Paris, and Middle East., circa 1982-1986 (Box 33, Folder 6-7)
  - Yemen, Iran, and Italy., 1973-1983 (Box 38, Folder 5, Box 36, Folder 7, Box 33, Folder 8-10)
  - Yosemite National Park., 1983 (Box 33, Folder 11)